<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>1. Connect on Ops2Devops Workshop documentation</title><link>https://ops2devops.tanzu.dk/1.connect/</link><description>Recent content in 1. Connect on Ops2Devops Workshop documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 20:33:12 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ops2devops.tanzu.dk/1.connect/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>01 Ipadresses</title><link>https://ops2devops.tanzu.dk/1.connect/1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 20:33:12 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ops2devops.tanzu.dk/1.connect/1/</guid><description>All Student ipadresses are shared from a Notion page, found here. Dont copy them, until the teacher has updated with the ipadessed, relevant for the current class. You will be given a student number. Each student has a public ipadress. Write it down, since you will use it many times today.
Also write down the public ipadress of the Kubernetes Cluster (Also found on the page)</description></item><item><title>02 Connect to environment</title><link>https://ops2devops.tanzu.dk/1.connect/2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 20:33:12 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ops2devops.tanzu.dk/1.connect/2/</guid><description>We will now connect to the VScode environment.
Open the browser you are going to use for VScode (Firefox or Chrome), and open the url http://studentip:8080 When you see the login page, login using VMware1! Select I understand on the warning box in the bottom right. You can run thru the getting started guide, or just select mark done. It&amp;rsquo;s up to you.</description></item><item><title>03 Understand VScode</title><link>https://ops2devops.tanzu.dk/1.connect/3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 20:33:12 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ops2devops.tanzu.dk/1.connect/3/</guid><description>This course will be using VScode for everyting. We will run thru the basics, so you know the tool, you will be working with.
In the top left corner, you will see the main controls of VScode.
Submenu Files Search Git Debug Extentions In this workshop, we will be using Submenu, Files, Git and extentions.</description></item></channel></rss>